Ruth Tiffany Barnhouse papers SSC.MS.00202
Sophia Smith Collection
- Ruth Tiffany Barnhouse personal and professional papers, 1951-1996; 1976-1996; 4; 8.437 linear feet (10 containers)
  - Correspondence with Michael Krausz and Connie Costigan, 1978-1989 (Box 5)
  - Correspondence with Barbara Long, Fred Licciardi, and Kevin Lewis, 1992-1994 (Box 5)
  - Correspondence with Alan Levenson, 1993 (Box 5)
  - Correspondence with Almut Liese, 1989-1996 (Box 5)
  - Correspondence with Marjorie Marquis, 1984-1988 (Box 5)
  - Letter to Lee Martindale, 1993 (Box 5)
  - Correspondence with Martin Marty, 1992 (Box 5)
  - Letter to William May, 1990 (Box 5)
  - Correspondence from Daniel Mayer, 1989 (Box 5)
  - Chain letter supporting abolition of South African apartheid, filed under "M. Mboya", 1990 (Box 5)
  - Letter from Billie H. McAnally, 1989 (Box 5)
  - Correspondence with H. Neill McFarland, 1989, 1991 (Box 5)
  - Correspondence with Bobbie McGuffie, 1979-1984 (Box 5)
  - Letter to J. Pittman McGehee, 1990 (Box 5)
  - Correspondence with Dorothy McMurray, 1985 (Box 5)
  - Correspondence with Dennis McNally, 1972-1994 (Box 5)
  - Letter from Robert Jay Lifton, 1991 (Box 5)
  - Correspondence with Sheila Long, 1979-1996; 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Correspondence with Henry Zvi Lothane, 1995 (Box 5)
  - Miscellaneous "M" correspondence, 1981-1996 (Box 5)
    Includes one-off correspondence with various people whose names end in "M," including an exchange with Frances McCullough in 1981 about a Plath manuscript.
  - Correspondence with John Macquarrie, 1982-1983 (Box 5)
  - Correspondence with Leonard J. Marcel, 1991 (Box 5)
  - Barbara Middleton nomination for award, around 1985 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence with Elizabeth Middleton, 1990 (Box 6)
  - Draft and reprint by Jean Baker Miller, 1981 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence with Gavin Miller, 1989 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence with Chad Minifie, 1983-1985 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence from Paul C. Mohl, 1993 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence with Roger Molander, 1989 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence with Elizabeth Moberly, 1989-1994 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence with Celia Morris, 1993 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence with Bryce Morrison, 1991-1992 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence with John D. Moseley, 1991 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence with Deborah Nissen, 1989 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence with Theodore Nadelson, MD, 1986-1991 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence from Kimberly Nappo regarding her business, 1990 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence with Joseph Nicolosi regarding the National Association for Psychoanalytic Research and Treatment of Homosexuality (NARTH), 1992 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence with Barbara C. Niebruegge regarding Barnhouse's book on homosexuality, 1991 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence with Philip Novak regarding ICUS conference, 1991 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence with Barbara E. O'Connell and Marian Tomaz de Oliveira, 1989, 1994 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence with Dr. Martin Odermatt, 1992 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence with and photograph of Very Rev. Dr. Akin Ojumu, 1991-1992 (Box 6)
  - Letter to Frank E. Oliver, 1991 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence with Lori Palmer, Margaret Pederson, John F. Petty, and others, 1984-1995; 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Letter from Valerie P. Parsegian regarding Sheila Long, 1990 (Box 6)
  - Letter to Sohmi Patel, 1991 (Box 6)
  - Photocopy of "The Behavioral Sciences in a Christian Perspective," by E. Mansell Pattison, around 1990 (Box 6)
  - Correspondece with Scott Peck, 1985-1992 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence with Nan Peete, 1989-1990 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence with John (Jan) Perkins, 1992 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence with Martin H. Prozesky, 1990-1996 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence with Peter A. Prudden, 1989-1990 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence from Carolyn Bain and Bill Pugh, 1989-1995 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence with Jane Purtle, 1992 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence with Nancy Qualls-Corbett, 1989 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence with Kathryn Riddall, Nancy Remen, E.C. Rose, Aretta Rathmell, MaryAnn Roman, and Anita Rufus, 1989-1995 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence with Robert E. Ratelle, 1992 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence with Paul Radich and Erika Radich, 1963-1994 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence with Ravi Ravindra, 1992 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence with June and Bill Rees (Canon W. E. Rees), 1977, 1989; 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Correspondence with Lillian Harris Robinson, 1984-1996 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence with C.A. Rundell, Jr., 1991, 1993 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence with Kathy Ridall, 1972-1985 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence with David J. Rose and Renate Rose, 1974-1985 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence with Elizabeth C. Rose, 1973-1985 (Box 6)
  - Miscellaneous "S" Correspondence, 1988-1996 (Box 6)
    Includes correspondence with Linda Simon regarding a record of William James at McLean Hospital.
  - Correspondence with Elizabeth Rose, 1973-1988 (Box 6)
  - Newsletters and flyers from Marvin W. Sams, around 1990 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence with Rev. Lowell J. Satre, Jr., 1985 (Box 6)
    Correspondence regarding Barnhouse's book and views on homosexuality
  - Copies of correspondence by Dorothy L. Sayers in 1924-1925, around 1950-1980 (Box 6)
    Handwritten transcripts with a typed note: "Coies of letters written by Dorothy L. Sayers in 1924-5. Made by a friend who had access to these in Houghton Library before they were put away in the vault. He took care to space words on page and line just as she had."
  - Correspondence from Albert H. Schrut, 1991 (Box 6)
  - Letter from Mary Ann Scofield, 1991 (Box 6)
  - Letter to Marcia Scott, 1989 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence with Michael Semsch, 1992 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence with James Shaller, 1984 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence with William H. Sheldon "& coterie", approximately 1951-1965 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence with Dr. Yu-cun Shen, 1985, 19087 (Box 6)
  - Letter from Ursula Shone, 1990 (Box 6)
  - Letter to "Sidsel", 1990 (Box 6)
  - Letters to Jane Roberts and transcript of "ESP class" trance session in which Roberts channeled Seth for Barnhouse, 1972 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence with Jane Simon, 1991 (Box 6)
  - Letter to Shelly Simpson about Bruce Duncan, 1991 (Box 6)
  - Photocopy of a review of Beyond Freedom and Dignity by B. F. Skinner, 1972 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence with Carol Houck Smith about a book in progress titled Sex and War, 1985-1990 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence with Gwendoly Smythe, 1992 (Box 6)
  - Letter to John Spiegel, requesting he write in support of her membership on the APA Committee on Religion, 1989 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence with Robert M. Stein, 1974-1980 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence with Zug Standing-Bear, 1992 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence with James Stanton, 1993 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence with Ann Steel-Simmons, 1996 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence with Carol Stevenson and W. Taylor Stevenson, 1974-1994 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence with Robert J. Stoller, 1973 (Box 6)
  - Card fro H. Streich, 1989 (Box 6)
  - Christmas letter from the Sturman family, 1989 (Box 6)
  - Writing on Our Lady of Guadalupe by Edwin E. Sylvest, Jr., 1989 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence with and offprints from Ann R. Turkel, Around 1996 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence with John W. Turnbull, 1976-1991; 1977-1982 (Box 6)
    Like Barnhouse, Turnbull, also an Episcopal priest, was deeply involved in debates within the Episcopal church about homosexuality. The correspondence in this file is frequently, though not exclusively, on this topic.
  - Miscellaneous "T" correspondence, 1989-1995 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence with Antony Thomas, 1987-1996 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence with Cynthia L. Thompson, 1985-1988 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence with and clippings about Bishop K. H. Ting, 1982 (Box 6)
  - Clippings and resume for Margaret Ann Bolinger (d. 1986), as well as a bound history of S. H. Bollinger & Co., Ltd., around 1986 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence with Norman Todd, 1988 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence with Rev. Douglas Travis, 1989 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence with and on behalf of Michelle Travis, 1982-1985 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence from Grace Trenchero, 1991 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence with Rev. James Troust on Barnhouse's stance on homosexuality, 1993 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence with Montague Ullman, 1991 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence with Alex Ulanov, 1995-1996 (Box 6)
  - Reprints and correspondence with Ann Belford Ulanov, 1975-1996; 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Correspondence with Sister Benedicta Ward, S.L.G., 1971-1996; 2 folders (Box 7)
  - Letter to Tony and Julie VanHam, 1992 (Box 7)
  - Correspondence with Hugo Van Dooran, 1982-1990 (Box 7)
  - Miscellaneous "W" correspondence, 1989-1995 (Box 7)
  - Correspondence from Heather Wallace and Connie Downs of Coventry Cathedral, 1988 (Box 7)
  - Correspondence with Lynn Weiss, 1991 (Box 7)
  - Correspondence with Michael Whinney, 1983-1995 (Box 7)
  - Correspondence with Henry Wilmer, 1986-1991 (Box 7)
  - Correspondence and workshop information from Roger Wolger, 1987-1991; 3 folders (Box 7)
  - Correspondence with Betty Wright of Scottish Churches Council (Box 7)
  - Miscellaneous "XYZ" correspondence, 1989-1994 (Box 7)
  - Correspondence with N. S. Xavier, 1989 (Box 7)
  - Correspondence with David X. Young, 1970-1996; 3 folders (Box 7)
  - Correspondence with "Young, Harrison & MA & family", 1969, 1974, 1990 (Box 7)
  - James J. Young funeral rites materials, 1986 (Box 7)
  - Correspondence regarding homosexuality, 1970, 1976-1995; 1976-1995 (Box 7)
    Correspondence to and from Barnhouse on various subjects related to homosexuality and the church. Some is written by people who read Barnhouse's work; earlier correspondence includes her drafts and comments about writing her most widely read pieces on the topic, as well as letters with church leaders regarding a candidate for the priesthood whom Barnhouse alleged had made advances toward and "felt up" her sons. The file also includes Barnhouse's notes on the December 1969 AAAS meetings, which do not appear to have anything related to homosexuality.
  - Responses to article on Pastoral Theology in The Anglican Review, 1984 (Box 7)
  - Identity: Marketing, etc., 1984-1988 (Box 7)
  - Unfiled business correspondence, 1982-1989 (Box 7)
  - Correspondence with publisher Norton, 1982 (Box 7)
  - Correspondence about book Kuzumi-Kodansha, 1991-1993 (Box 7)
  - Studies in Jung -- RTB notes and materials regarding seminar, 1982-1993 (Box 7)
  - Correspondence with Westminster Press about Identity, 1984; 2 folders (Box 7)
  - Comments on Identity, 1984 (Box 7)
  - News Stories about Ruth Tiffany Barnhouse, 1981-1984 (Box 7)
  - Transcription of TV Talk Show, Mosiac on "Gay Rights" with Ruth Tiffany Barnhouse, 1977 (Box 7)
  - Unfiled Materials, including folder on Silva Mind Control, correspondence from the Society of the Inner Light, and a booklet Women in the Chinese Revolution by Laurie Landy, 1972-1974 (Box 7)
  - Responses to Channel 13 program, April 1988 (Box 7)
  - Short interviews and write-ups about Ruth Tiffany Barnhouse, 1976-1977 (Box 7)
  - Letters from readers about various articles, 1977-1979 (Box 7)
  - Letter to Psychiatric News re: ERA, 1978 (Box 7)
  - Lecture notes and writings by Ruth Tiffany Barnhouse on homosexuality and sexual relationships with former psychiatry patients, 1972-1992 (Box 7)
  - Correspondence with Seabury Press about homosexuality book, 1975-1976 (Box 7)
  - Ruth Tiffany Barnhouse's "Minorty Report" on homosexuality, 1978-1980 (Box 7)
  - Correspondence with Tony Campolo on homosexuality, 1991 (Box 7)
  - Reviews of Male and Female, 1976-1978 (Box 7)
  - Seabury Press - The Church's Teaching Series: Charleson Meeting, 1977 (Box 7)
  - Seabury Press correspondence regarding paperback edition of Homosexuality, 1979-1985 (Box 7)
  - Correspondence about Seabury Press - The Church's Teaching Series Volume VI, 1976-1978 (Box 7)
  - Quest Learning Center regarding "recovery from homosexuality", 1982-1984 (Box 7)
  - Unfiled correspondence regarding Barnhouse's article "What about Fundamentalism?" and other professional topics, 1993-1996 (Box 7)
  - Syllabi and exams from courses taught by Ruth Tiffany Barnhouse, 1978-1990 (Box 7)
  - Addresses of the participants at the "God: The Contemporary Discussion" conference, 1983 (Box 7)
  - Correspondence regarding APA Committee on Religion, 1985, 1994 (Box 7)
  - Correspondence related to employment at Metropolitan State Hospital, 1956-1957 (Box 7)
  - Correspondence and documents related to employment at Harvard University, 1955-1978 (Box 7)
  - Correspondence and documents related to employment at McLean Hospital, 1959-1978 (Box 7)
  - Correspondence and documents related to employment at Sibley Memorial Hospital, 1978-1980 (Box 7)
  - Manuscripts for "A Woman's Identity," "Male and Female," "Homosexuality, A Symbolic Confusion", 1975-1994; 1999-S-0014 (Box 13)
  - Publications and grey literature related to Community Psych Lab, 1968-1973 (Box 13)
  - Barnhouse's notes on review course in Psychiatry for ABPN, 1968-1970 (Box 13)
  - Audio recording "Spir. Ex. of St. Ignatius in Psych Perspective (Lecture), Loyola U., New Orleans", 1984 September 15; SP1a-SP1b; 2 items (2 audiocassettes) (Box 8)
  - Audio recording "Christian Spirituality", 1984 September 17; SP2a-SP2k; 11 items (11 audiocassettes) (Box 8)
  - Audio recording "Devotional Life", 1985 January 7; SP3a-SP3b; 2 items (2 audiocassettes) (Box 8)
  - Audio recording "Prayer and Spirituality", 1985 September 12; SP4a-SP4t; 20 items (20 audiocassettes) (Box 8)
  - Audio recording "Spir. Dev. Essential to Healthy Ps.", 1986 November 9; SP6; 20 items (20 audiocassettes) (Box 8)
  - Audio recording "Are there any differences between the prayer life of men and women?" in Perth, 1987 August 12; SP8; 1 items (1 audiocassette) (Box 8)
  - Audio recording "Is there a connection between devotional and real life?" in Perth, 1987 July 29; SP9; 1 items (1 audiocassette) (Box 8)
  - Audio recording "Is one's prayer life influenced by psychological factors?" in Perth, 1987 August 5; SP10; 1 items (1 audiocassette) (Box 8)
  - Audio recording "Landscape - spir. journey" at The Church of St John the Divine, Houston, TX, 1988 March 9; SP11; 1 items (1 audiocassette) (Box 8)
  - Audio recording "Leuten Program - St. Francis Church", 1989 March 15; SP12; 1 items (1 audiocassette) (Box 8)
  - Audio recording "Prayer and Moral Progress", 1989 February 14; SP13; 1 items (1 audiocassette) (Box 8)
  - Audio recording "The Church Year Retreat, Transfiguration, Dallas", 1990 December 1; SP14a-SP14b; 2 items (2 audiocassettes) (Box 8)
  - Audio recording "Prayer Class", 1990 September 17 - 1990 November 19; SP15a-SP15j; 10 items (10 audiocassettes) (Box 8)
  - Audio recording "Prayer course", 1990 November 12; SP16; 1 items (1 audiocassette) (Box 8)
  - Audio recording "Spirituality and Psychotherapy: Partners or Strangers", 1993 June 6-13; SP17a-SP17b; 2 items (2 audiocassettes) (Box 8)
  - Audio recording "Christian Emphasis Week Assembly", 1993 March 19; SP18; 1 items (1 audiocassette) (Box 8)
  - Audio recording "Spirituality and Stress", 1995 January 21; SP19a-SP19b; 2 items (2 audiocassettes) (Box 8)
  - Audio recording "Study", 1978 November 19; 1 items (1 audiocassette) (Box 8)
  - Audio recording "Barnhouse TRANSCRIBE", 1982 April 8; 1 items (1 audiocassette) (Box 8)
  - Audio recording "Episcopal Sem. SW Ethics Class", April 23; 1 items (1 audiocassette) (Box 8)
  - Audio recording "Prayer and Spirituality", 1992 January 26; 1 items (1 audiocassette) (Box 8)
  - Audio recording "Women as Caregivers: Nature or Nurture?", approximately 1974-1995; 1 items (1 audiocassette) (Box 8)
  - Audio recording "Sitting by the Well" by Marion Woodman, 1993; Tape 1-2; 2 items (2 audiocassettes) (Box 8)
  - Audio recording "Sex and the Ware Impulse" on 613 WKHO, "Mon. 3:30-5pm," approximately 1974-1995; 1 items (1 audiocassette) (Box 8)
  - Audio recording "Healing the Healers (Keynote)", approximately 1980-1995; 1 items (1 audiocassette) (Box 8)
  - Audio recording "Fundamentalism", 1992 June 26; 2 items (2 audiocassettes) (Box 8)
  - Audio recording "Lecture I", 1995 October 20; 1 items (1 audiocassette) (Box 8)
  - Audio recording "Advent", 1995 November 19; 1 items (1 audiocassette) (Box 8)
  - Audio recording "Being Anglican in late 20th C", 1996 March 13; 1 items (1 audiocassette) (Box 8)
  - Audio recording "Jungian Archetypes and Church Year", 1983 November 03; PR1; 1 items (1 audiocassette) (Box 9)
  - Audio recording "Science and Religion", 1982 January 31; PR2a-PR2e; 5 items (5 audiocassettes) (Box 9)
  - Audio recording "Wilson Lectures (3)", 1981 October 6-7; PR3; 1 items (1 audiocassette) (Box 9)
  - Audio recording "Value Systems", 1976; PR4; 1 items (1 audiocassette) (Box 9)
  - Audio recording "Analytic Psychotherapy", 1979; PR5; 1 items (1 audiocassette) (Box 9)
  - Audio recording "Psalm: Pastoral Counseling and Education Center", 1980 November 2; PR6; 1 items (1 audiocassette) (Box 9)
  - Audio recording "Special Panel: Alger, Rothman, Macklin, Kovel, Barnhouse", approximately 1974-1995; PR7a-PR7b; 2 items (2 audiocassettes) (Box 9)
  - Audio recording "Christian Symbolism and the Process of Individuation", 1981 April 4; PR8a-PR8b; 2 items (2 audiocassettes) (Box 9)
  - Audio recording "Lindey Jones PC+C", 1983 April 7-29; PR9a-PR9e; 5 items (5 audiocassettes) (Box 9)
  - Audio recording "Psych and spiritual", approximately 1974-1995; PR10; 1 items (1 audiocassette) (Box 9)
  - Audio recording "TV- Radius RTB, DGB, Canon Wiltkouske and Rev 'Haurey'", 1972 May 12; PR11; 1 items (1 audiocassette) (Box 9)
  - Audio recording "Christian Symbolism and the Process of Individuation", 1980 May 10-11; PR12a-PR12e; 5 items (5 audiocassettes) (Box 9)
  - Audio recording "Idealism IS Practical!", 1984 January 29; PR13a-PR13b; 2 items (2 audiocassettes) (Box 9)
  - Audio recording "Religious Symbolism, Individuation", 1981 April 3; PR14; 1 items (1 audiocassette) (Box 9)
  - Audio recording "Science and Religion", 1982 April 24; PR15a-PR15b; 2 items (2 audiocassettes) (Box 9)
  - Audio recording "Science and Religion", 1982 February 14; PR16; 1 items (1 audiocassette) (Box 9)
  - Audio recording "COP", 1984 March 20; PR17; 1 items (1 audiocassette) (Box 9)
  - Audio recording "Sin Seminar", 1983 November 19; PR18a-PR18c; 3 items (3 audiocassettes) (Box 9)
  - Audio recording "Jesus: Perfect Past. Counselor", 1986 April 2-4; PR19a-PR19e; 5 items (5 audiocassettes) (Box 9)
  - Audio recordings "What Only Pastoral Care Can Do," "What Psychotherapy Does Best," and "Pastoral Care and Psychotherapy Compared", 1986; PR20a-PR20c; 3 items (3 audiocassettes) (Box 9)
  - Audio recording "Vision of the Fulfilled Person: Psychodynamic and Religious Perspectives", approx 1986-1988; PR21a-PR21b; 2 items (2 audiocassettes) (Box 9)
  - Audio recording "Emotions and Faith", 1988 January 17-31; PR22a-PR22b; 2 items (2 audiocassettes) (Box 9)
  - Audio recording "Differentiating Normal from Pathological Religious Ideation", approximately 1974-1995; PR23a-PR23b; 1 items (1 audiocassette) (Box 9)
  - Audio recording "Psychotherapy and Religion: What Can the Lay Person Expect from Each?", 1988 October 28; PR24; 1 items (1 audiocassette) (Box 9)
  - Audio recordings "The Collective Shadow: Dangers of Mass Projections in the Nuclear Age" and "Psychiatry and Religion: Parallels and Problems", approximately 1974-1995; PR25a-PR25c; 3 items (3 audiocassettes) (Box 9)
  - Audio recording "What Can One Woman Do?", 1991 Feburary 12; PR26; 1 items (1 audiocassette) (Box 9)
  - Audio recording "Paper Session III: Religion-- Faith-- the Spiritual; Psychoanalysis and Faith; Rage at God and Transformation", approximately 1991; PR27a-PR27b; 2 items (2 audiocassettes) (Box 9)
  - Audio recording "Religion and the Afterlife", 1991 April 28; PR28; 2 items (2 audiocassettes) (Box 9)
  - Audio recording "Fundamentalism", 1992 June 26; PR29a-PR29b; 2 items (2 audiocassettes) (Box 9)
  - Audio recording "Gaia Theory," Kera Denard Show, 1990 April 25; PR30; 1 items (1 audiocassette) (Box 9)
  - Audio recording "RTB and A. McKinney from Fund. Anonymous", 1989 July 26; PR31; 1 items (1 audiocassette) (Box 9)
  - Audio recording "Healing the Healers", 1990 June 13; PR32a-PR32b; 2 items (2 audiocassettes) (Box 9)
  - Audio recording "Birmingham Cathedral", 1990 June 12; PR33a-PR33b; 2 items (2 audiocassettes) (Box 9)
  - Audio recording "Religion and Medicine", 1991 May 24; PR34a-PR34b; 2 items (2 audiocassettes) (Box 9)
  - Audio recording "Healing the Healers", 1991 July 15; PR35; 1 items (1 audiocassette) (Box 9)
  - Audio recording "Getting Friendly w/God", 1990 December 16; PR36; 1 items (1 audiocassette) (Box 9)
  - Audio recording "Nobody Told Me It Was Impossible", 1989 December 1; PR37; 1 items (1 audiocassette) (Box 9)
  - Audio recording, 1989 March 6; PR38a-PR38b; 2 items (2 audiocassettes) (Box 9)
  - Audio recording "Psychiatry and Faith: A Contemporary Perspective", 1993 May 25; PR39a-PR39b; 2 items (2 audiocassettes) (Box 9)
  - Audio recording "When I'm Hurting, Whom do I Call?", 1993 February 21; PR40; 1 items (1 audiocassette) (Box 9)
  - Audio recording "M/F Equality", 1994 January 30; PR41; 1 items (1 audiocassette) (Box 9)
  - Audio recording "Christian Emphasis Week Assembly Speaker: Dr. Barnhouse", 1993 March 18; PR42; 1 items (1 audiocassette) (Box 9)
  - Audio recording "PsychoRx and Spirituality", 1994 October 21; PR44a-PR44c; 3 items (3 audiocassettes) (Box 9)
  - Audio recordings "The Significance of the New DSMIV Diagnostic Category," "Psychotherapy and Spirituality," "The Effects of Sexuality on the Spiritual Experience," "The Effects of Psychological Type on the Spiritual Experience", 1995 January 13; PR45a-PR45d; 4 items (4 audiocassettes) (Box 9)
  - Audio recording "New Ways to Interact with 'Strangers'", 1995 March 23-25; PR46a-PR46b; 2 items (2 audiocassettes) (Box 9)
  - Audio recording "Religious Problems cont'd", 1995 April 6; PR47; 1 items (1 audiocassette) (Box 9)
  - Audio recording "Soul Care in Grad Schools", 1995 April 21; PR48; 1 items (1 audiocassette) (Box 9)
  - Audio recording "LPMA", 1995 September 30; PR49a-PR49b; 2 items (2 audiocassettes) (Box 9)
  - Audio recording "Consider the Alternatives #492: The Joys of Nuclear War", approximately 1974-1995; OP1; 1 items (1 audiocassette) (Box 10)
  - Audio recording "The Universe of Many Dimensions", 1985 March 31; OP2; 1 items (1 audiocassette) (Box 10)
  - Audio recording "Women and Religion", 1972 March 25; OP3; 1 items (1 audiocassette) (Box 10)
  - Audio recordings "The Incredible Love of God," "An Open Universe," "God Still Heals," "Allowing God to Love Through Me," "Confessions of an Anxiety Neurotic", 1978; OP4a-OP4e; 5 items (5 audiocassettes) (Box 10)
  - Audio recordings "William Church as a Psychological Crucible," "Jung's Challenge to Contemporary Religion", 1985; OP5a-OP5b; 2 items (2 audiocassettes) (Box 10)
  - Audio recording "Holy Trinity", 1982 September 15; OP6a-OP6b; 2 items (2 audiocassettes) (Box 10)
  - Audio recording "The Problem of Peace - given at First Presb. Church, Bartlesville, Okla.", 1982 February 21; OP7a-OP7b; 2 items (2 audiocassettes) (Box 10)
  - Audio recording "3rd Week, R. Doherty", approximately 1974-1995; OP8; 1 items (1 audiocassette) (Box 10)
  - Audio recording "Meditation and Cancer", approximately 1974-1995; OP9; 1 items (1 audiocassette) (Box 10)
  - Audio recording "The Role of the Mind in Cancer Therapy", approximately 1974-1995; OP10; 1 items (1 audiocassette) (Box 10)
  - Audio recording "Introduction", 1979; OP11; 1 items (1 audiocassette) (Box 10)
  - Audio recording "The Misuse of Psychiatry to Suppress Dissent", 1977; OP12; 1 items (1 audiocassette) (Box 10)
  - Audio recording "Reach of the Mind," "Reflections and Directions", 1985 February 9; OP13a-OP13b; 2 items (2 audiocassettes) (Box 10)
  - Audio recording "The Beginning and End of the Universe Seen Through a Cloud Darkly", 1985 October 4; OP14a-OP14b; 2 items (2 audiocassettes) (Box 10)